Win at Nationals!
駒場って前からあんなだっけ？
Was Komaba always like this?
He's doing well.
調子いいでしょう
秋大会にばっちり合わせてきてますよ
It's just in time for
the fall tournament.
いや　何つーかな…
Well, it's just that...
殺気放っとる
He's so intense...
本格的な夏の日差しが
肌を焦がしていく様に
私もあなたに恋焦がれる
海へドライブ 運転するよ
横顔撫でる 潮風が気持ちいいsummer day
la la la summer day
ビーチパラソルカラフルだ yeah
砂浜に咲く 花みたい
KISS YOU あなたの心
もっともっと近くにいたい 感じたい
私だけ見て
KISS YOU ぐっと膨らんだ
胸の思い 唇にのせて 伝えたいと
だから KISS YOU
だから さあ KISS YOU
できた
Done!
うわー　出来たてのベーコンって初めて見た
Wow, I've never seen
fresh bacon before!
Episode 11
Take Off Running,
Hachiken
結構いい感じだな
Looks pretty good.
Yeah!
はい
The cheese and eggs are
looking good, too.
チーズも卵も奇麗にできてる
What's with the cheese and eggs?
何だ　そのチーズやら卵やらは
勝手に薫製を増やしおって
Who said you could smoke them, too?
しょうがないやつらだ
You guys are just hopeless.
富士先生こそ何ですか　それ
But what about you,
Fuji-sensei? What's that?
It's teaching material!
教材だ
発酵食品と加工肉との親和性を検証する
I will evaluate the compatibility of fermented
food products with processed meats!
駄目な教師だ
You're a horrible teacher!
It's already after work hours.
もう勤務時間外だしな
いや　ここ学校の敷地内なんですけど
Uh, you're still on school grounds.
Okay.
じゃ　みんなで味見しよーぜ
Let's do a taste test.
Yeah!
やったー！
Yum!
うまっ！
チーズもうまいっすね
The cheese is good, too.
うん　いけるな
Yeah, they're great.
Have some smoked cheese, Sensei!
先生もスモークチーズどうぞ
「どうぞ」ってもともと私のチーズじゃないですか
It was my cheese in the first place!
Wouldn't it be even better to
fry up some thick slices?
これ厚切りで焼いたらもっとおいしいんじゃない？
太るぅぅぅ！
No!
We'll get fat!
じゃあ　そこで出た油で刻みニンニク炒めて
Then we can fry minced garlic
and rice in the bacon grease
and make soy-sauce flavored fried rice!
ご飯入れてしょうゆチャーハン
ジャァスティィィス！
Bacon garlic fried rice!
Justice!
We'll get so fat!
肥えるわ！
You trying to kill us?
殺す気か！
Unbelievable!
けしからん！
うめぇ…
So good...
ホントうまいっすねー
Really good.
Cheers!
かんぱ～い！
Thanks for the food!
いただきま～す！
Why are you still here?!
何でまだいんだよ
よお　今小麦畑の短期バイトでエゾノーに来てんだよ
Hey!
I'm here at Ezonoo for temp
labor in the wheat fields.
うわっ　八軒の兄ちゃんだ
Hey, it's Hachiken's bro!
The killer yakisoba guy!
殺人焼きそばの人だ
I was just checking out where the
great smell was coming from,
なんかいい匂いするから来てみたら　これだもんなー
and look what I found!
いいもん食わせてもらったわー
Thanks for the great food!
Hachiken-kun made 50 kilos of bacon.
八軒君が作ったんですよ
５０ｋｇのベーコン
Yuugo did this?
勇吾が？
Wow...
What? Just leave
once you're done eating!
Yeah! We're having a Bacon Fest!
何だよ
ベーコン祭り開催するわよ！
食ったらさっさと帰れよ
御影　実家にベーコン送っとくよ
Mikage, I'll send some
to your family, too.
They took good care of
me over the summer.
夏休み世話になったからさ
ありがと　みんな喜ぶよ
Thanks!
That'll make them really happy!
駒場んちにも…
I'll send Komaba's family some, too...
あれ？　駒場は？
Oh, where's Komaba?
まだ練習じゃないかな
He must still be at practice.
I know his address.
いっちゃんちの住所なら分かるよ
Yuugo, send some home, to Sapporo.
勇吾　札幌の実家にも送っとけよ
えっ！？　何でだよ　必要ないだろ
Huh, why?!
I don't need to!
必要とかそういうんじゃなくてさ
It's not about whether
you need to or not.
親が喜ぶだろ
It'd make our parents happy, right?
No way!
喜ぶわけないだろ
I bet they'll just think it has
nothing to do with entrance exams.
「受験の足しにもならないことして！」って
どうせあきれてバカにされるに決まってる
They'll just throw their hands up
in the air and look down on me.
Hey, it's not about entrance exams.
だからさ　受験の足しとかそういうんじゃないんだって
お前の本気を見せてやれっての
Show them what you're capable of!
Later.
じゃあな
Wait!
待てよ
ポケットの中身置いてけ！
Empty out your pockets.
I'll be sticking around for a while.
しばらくこの辺にいるから
Text me if you need anything!
何かあったらメールよこせよー
I don't have your info on my phone!
兄貴のアドレスなんざ登録してねえ！
H-Hey, wait!
待て　こら　逃げんなー！
You're not getting away!
They're very close.
仲のいい兄弟ですな
ですな
Indeed.
Ooezo Agricultural High School Dormitory for Future Agriculture Managers
Bacon
よしっと
All right.
Here they are.
お願いします
両方とも中身ベーコン？
Are they both bacon?
じゃ冷蔵２つな
Both refrigerated packages, then.
よろしくお願いします
Thank you.
Show them what you're capable of!
お前の本気を見せてやれっての
あの…伝票もう１枚もらえますか
Um, may I have another shipping label?
Dairy Science
あの…八軒君呼んでもらえる？
Um, can you get Hachiken-kun?
八軒君　お客さん
Hachiken-kun, someone's here to see you!
It's Ikeda, from Food Processing.
食品科の池田じゃん
What is it?
何？
あの…
Um...
ほら　言っちゃいなよ
C'mon, tell him.
えっ？　やっぱ恥ずかしい
I dunno, I'm embarrassed...
言いにくいなら私が言おうか？
Want me to say it, then?
いや　待って　自分で言うから
No, wait! I'll ask, myself!
Huh?!
えっ！？
What? What?
えっ？　えっ？　う…　何これ！
What's going on?
あの…　八軒君
Um, Hachiken-kun!
はい
Yes?
ベーコン売ってください！
Please sell me bacon!
Yeah!
やったー！
Let's go make pizza!
ピザ焼こう！　ピザ！
己　八軒！
Damn you, Hachiken!
Damn it!
チクショー　俺もベーコン作って女にモテてえ！
I wanna make bacon and be
popular with the girls, too!
アキ　コロッケ落ちたよ
Aki, you dropped your croquette.
おう　八軒はいるか
Hey, Hachiken here?
Give us bacon!
ベーコンよこせや
Now the third-years are here!
今度は３年だよ
Scary!
怖え
Um, what do you mean?
あの…どういうことでしょうか
俺ら金ねえからよぉ
We don't have money, see?
分かってんだろ？　あぁ？
You know what we mean, don't you?
Hmm?!
R-Right!
は…はい！
End of the Century
Pork Bowl...
豚ど～ん！
豚丼…豚どん！
Pork Bowl!
物々交換でいいかな？
Can we just trade you
something in return?
えっ？
Huh?
Strawberry Jam
Here.
これ　うちのいちごジャム
This is our strawberry jam.
野菜
Veggies.
トマトソース
Tomato sauce.
Thanks!
ありがとなー！
またベーコン作ったら教えろや
Let us know next time you make bacon!
モテモテだな
You're a hot item.
変な学校…
This school's so weird.
I wasn't sure I could eat
50 kilos of meat,
５０ｋｇの肉って食べきれるのか不安だったけど
あっちゅー間になくなりそうだな
but I guess it won't be long
before it's all gone.
If you still have some
left, sell me some, too.
まだ余ってたら僕にも売ってよ
Oh, sure.
おー　いいよ
今度僕も１頭買ってベーコン作ってみようかな
Maybe next time I'll buy one pig's
worth and make bacon, too...
八千代先生に教えてもらったんだけど
Yachiyo-sensei told me that vets
work at slaughterhouses, too.
と畜場にも獣医が常駐してるんだって
へえ～　そうなの？
Oh, really?
現場で畜体検査して消費者に健康な肉を提供する仕事
They inspect animals there
to make sure that consumers
are getting healthy meat.
So there are lots of kinds, huh?
はあー　色々あるんだな
うん　獣医の仕事って意外と幅広いし
Yeah, I guess there's a broad
range of veterinary careers,
まだやりようはいくらでもあるよね
so I've got a lot of options!
Good luck!
頑張れよ
じゃーな
Later.
今度の試合　先発するんでしょ？
You're starting in the next game, right?
頑張ってね
Good luck.
Thanks.
おう
Really?!
マジで？　１年でかよ！？
As a first-year?!
もうお前のバットじゃかすりもしねーよ
You've got no hope
of hitting my pitches anymore.
甲子園行って　うまくいったらプロ入って
I'll go to nationals and,
if I'm lucky, I'll go pro.
What's wrong with being greedy?!
欲張りで何が悪い！
うちの経営は俺が立て直す！
I'm going to reinvigorate...
our business!
相手の五条って結構強いんでしょ？
The school you'll be up against,
Gojou, is pretty strong, right?
去年　うちを破ってベスト４だ
Yeah, they beat us and were
ranked fourth last year.
大丈夫かよ…
You gonna be okay?
俺は勝つしかねーからよ
I only know how to win!
駒場君　頼もしいよねー
You can really count on Komaba-kun.
僕もあんなふうに自信持てたらなー
I wish I could be as confident as him.
お疲れさまです
Nice job!
Thanks!
よう
ずいぶん早いですね
You were going really fast.
Yeah.
おう　今月末の大会で俺ら３年は引退だからさ
We third-years are going to retire
after the tournament
at the end of the month.
結果残しときたいじゃん
I want to go out with a bang, y'know?
I see...
そっか…
大会終わったら　就職活動に本腰入れなきゃならんし
Once the tournament's over,
I'll have to focus on my job search.
最後の青春？　みたいな
So this is like my last hurrah.
Senpai, are you thinking of a
job that involves horses?
先輩はやっぱ馬関係の仕事に？
Thanks.
サンキュー
いや　近場でいい所があればどんな会社でもいいと思ってる
Nah, I don't really care as long
as it's a good job that's close-by.
夢とかないんすか
Don't you have a dream or something?
夢？　別になぁ…
Dream?
Not really.
俺そういうのにこだわりないし
I'm not really obsessed about anything.
If nothing else,
あえて言うならのんべんだらりと生きたい
I want to do as little as possible.
そっすか
I see...
It's super cool to find
a job that suits you,
自分に合った仕事に就くってのはもちろんカッコイイけどさ
自分を仕事に合わせるってのもありだと思うんだ
but I think it's okay to
make yourself suit the job.
馬に乗るのも似たようなもんだし
It's not that different
from riding horses.
Horses?
馬？
自分に合った馬に乗るのは楽でいいですけど
It's easy to ride a
horse that suits you,
馬の個性に自分を合わせていく乗り方も面白いですよ
but it's also fun to adjust how
you ride to suit the horse.
Oh...
I thought this school
was full of people
ここの学校に来てるのって
将来なりたいものがしっかりある人ばっかだと思ってた
who had a clear image of what
they wanted to be in the future.
That might be because our
class has a lot of students
うちのクラスは後継ぎが多いから
who'll succeed their family business.
特にそう感じるんじゃない？
I see.
そっか
先輩たちは引退とか進路とか考える時期なんだね
I guess our senpais are
starting to think about
retiring from their clubs and
what they'll do next.
入学してもうすぐ半年か
It's been almost six months
since I came here.
That sure went by in a flash.
あっという間だったなー
目標みたいなもの見つかった？
Did you figure out what
you might want to do?
全然！
Nope!
溺れながら死ぬこともできずに流されてる感じ
I've just been drowning,
somehow avoiding death,
while being swept along with the current.
Whether it's about Pork
Bowl or my own future,
豚丼のことにしろ　将来のことにしろ
何だかずっと迷走してんだよなぁ
I'm just running around, lost.
ホント　俺どこに向かってんだろ
I wonder where I'm headed, really...
That's not true.
そんなことないよ
I think you're moving forward.
八軒君はちゃんと前に進んでると思うよ
Hello, Hachiken-kun.
こんにちは　八軒君
Thank you for the bacon.
ベーコン　ごちそうさまでした
校長先生も食べたんですか
You had some, too?
はい　とってもおいしかったです
Yes! It was delicious!
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
あ…食品科の稲田先輩にも手伝ってもらって
Oh, Inada-senpai from Food
Processing helped, too.
Every time I did it,
the bacon came out all lumpy.
慣れないから形もよれよれで
いや　その…あんなんでおいしいって言っていただけて…すいません
Well, I'm humbled that you liked it.
Thank you.
Hachiken-kun, you were
also apologizing when we
八軒君は夢の話をしたときも謝ってたけど
talked about your dreams.
自信がないのかな？　うん？
Do you lack confidence?
Well, I got picked on a lot
during junior high...
何か中学時代はずっと否定されてきて…
進学コース外れてこっち逃げてきちゃったんで…その…
I couldn't cut it in college admissions prep,
so I ran away and come here. So...
八軒君は「逃げる」ということに否定的なのだね
So you feel negative about
the idea of running away.
逃げてきたことに負い目はあっても
You may feel guilt over
having run away,
その逃げた先で起こったこと　そこで出会った人
but what about what happened here?
The people you've met?
How's it all been?
それらはどうでしたか？
否定するものでしたか？
Were they negative experiences?
No...
いえ…
It's okay to run away in order to live.
生きるための逃げはありです
ありありです
It's entirely okay.
あり…
Okay?
そう
Yes, you're different from farm animals,
who have nowhere to run.
逃げ場のない経済動物と君たちは違うんですから
逃げ場のない…
Nowhere to run...
うちは一人っ子だから
Besides, I'm the only child,
後継がないと家つぶすことになるし
so if I don't carry on,
the farm will go under.
I'm the only one who can
carry on the business.
俺が継がねえと　誰もやるやついねえから
逃げられないやつはどうしたらいいんでしょうか
What should people who don't
have anywhere to run do?
友達？
You mean your friends?
Er, well, um, yes...
いや…その…はい
Even though you've got
your hands full,
自分のことで手いっぱいっぽいのに友達のことも？
you're worried about your friends?
Oh, I'm sorry.
あっ　すいません
俺　色々吐き出し過ぎですよね
I blurted out too much.
Don't be.
いや　自分の気持ちをうまく言葉にできるから
I think you can "blurt out" like that
because you're good at
expressing yourself in words.
そうして吐き出せるのだと思います
Some students struggle to
talk about how they feel,
苦しくてもうまく本音を吐き出せない子もいるから
even though they're suffering.
そういう子に気付いたら　力になってあげてください
If you notice anyone like that,
please help them.
逃げたことを卑下しないで　それをプラスに変えてこそ
Don't look down on
yourself for running.
Make it meaningful by making
something out of it.
逃げたかいがあるというものです
O-Okay.
はい
Thank you.
ありがとうございました
俺　部活に戻ります
I'll go back to my club now.
八軒君
Hachiken-kun.
Yes?
はい
Please get me down.
下ろして
どうやって上ったんですか
How did you get up there?
2013 High School
Fall Baseball Tournament
Hokkaido Tokachi Division Preliminaries
よろしくお願いしま～す！
Let's have a good game!
おっ　やっぱ駒場のやつスタメンじゃん
Hey, Komaba really is
on the starting lineup.
俺　生で野球見るの初めてだ
I've never been to a
baseball game before.
Wow...
すげー
こんなバカでかい場所のど真ん中で投げなきゃいけないのか
He has to pitch from the center
of that giant place? It's so huge.
１年でこんな責任背負うなんて
That's so much responsibility
for a first-year.
I can't imagine the pressure.
どんだけのプレッシャーだよ
Komaba's awesome.
駒場　すげー
えっ？　何？　何？
Huh? What?
They got a hit off Komaba already?
駒場いきなり打たれてんの？
まだ始まったばかりだぞ！
The game's just started!
You'll have your chance!
ここから　ここから！
Man, this is nervewracking.
うあ　はらはらする
お前　そんなんで９回まで持つのかよ
Are you gonna last till
the ninth inning?
さあ　エゾノー　ツーアウトランナー生きる
All right, Ezonoo has a runner
on first and two outs.
どうです？
How's it looking?
粘って粘って抑えてますよ
バッターの…
The batter, Iwauchi, is standing strong
as the count is full.
They're holding on with
all they've got.
１‐０で負けてますが
They're losing 1-0,
そろそろ１発欲しいですねぇ
but maybe we can hope for a hit.
He connects!
打った！　長打になる！　一塁ランナーは…
It's a long ball!
The lead runner advances to third!
All right!
よっしゃ～！　二・三塁！
We've got a runner on
second and third base!
…ツーベースヒット！
He gets a double!
Uryuu-san, we're counting on you!
雨竜さん　頼んまーす！
The next batter is No. 7, Uryuu-kun.
７番雨竜君の打順です
U-ryu-u! U-ryu-u!
In his first at bat, he struck out looking at three breaking balls
最初の打席は変化球を見逃し三振でした
He hits the first pitch!
初球打ち！
The runner from second also scores!
Yeah!
五条　１点リードの４回
With Gojou leading 1-0 in the fourth inning,
Gojou
Ezonou
Uryuu-kun's run-scoring double
has given Ezonoo the lead!
雨竜君の２点タイムリーで一気に逆転したエゾノー
５回にも１点を加えますが
Ezonoo scored another run
in the fifth inning,
五条も次の回に１点を返して…
but Gojou returned the favor
in the sixth inning...
Yeah!
ありがとうございました
Thank you!
どうした？
What's wrong?
You're out if you lose
even once, right?
１回でも負けたら終わっちゃうんだよな
Yeah.
ああ
で　甲子園行けても
And even if you make it to nationals,
そこからさらにプロになる夢がかなうのって…
what are the chances that your
dreams of going pro come true?
そんなやつはほんの一握りだろうなぁ
They'd be pretty slim.
駒場　お疲れ～
Nice job, Komaba!
見てたぞ
We were watching you!
おう　応援来てくれたのか
Oh, you came to cheer me on?
…って　打たれたの見てたのかよ
Wait, I guess you saw
my pitch get hit.
I mean, it was amazing!
いや…何かすごかった
I don't know anything about
baseball, but... it was amazing!
俺　野球知らないけど　何かこう…
すごかった！
おう　俺がミスってもうちの先輩リカバリーがすげーからな
Yeah! Even though I messed up, our senpais
sure can pick up the pieces!
Quit braggin'!
威張んな
Post-game meeting time! Let's go!
反省会だ　行くぞ
うっす
'Kay!
雨竜さん　あの逆転のタイムリー　ありがとうございました
Uryuu-san, thanks for that clutch hit.
おう　一生恩に着ろよ
Sure!
You'll owe me for the
rest of your life!
あっ　ちょうどバスが来る時間だ
Oh, the bus is coming.
早く帰ろうぜ
Let's head back.
俺…走って帰る
I'll jog back.
俺も…
Me, too...
俺も
Me three.
はあ！？
おなかすいた
I'm starving!
駒場　次も投げるのかな？
I wonder if Komaba's gonna
pitch again in the next game.
どうだろ　エースもいるしね
I'm not sure.
They have an ace.
何？　どうしたの？　みんな
What's with everyone?
They're all fired up,
何かがたぎったから寮まで走って帰るって
so they're gonna run back to the dorm.
アホだ
Idiots!
別府は走らないの？
You're not gonna join them, Beppu?
やだ
No way!
八軒く～ん　夕方の馬の世話あるから
Hachiken-kun!
Make sure you save some energy
for the evening stable chores!
体力残しといてね～
了解！
Okay!
I have to...
何か…　何かやらなきゃ…
I have to do something!
何かやりたい！
I want to do something!
八軒さん　お荷物です
Hachiken-san, you have a delivery.
Coming!
はい
Bacon?
ベーコン？
Dear, Yuugo sent us bacon.
あなた
勇吾がベーコン送ってきたわよ
Hello!
こんちは～
You have a delivery.
お届け物で～す
やっぱり
I knew it!
たまには手紙を書いてみようよ
どっかにポストカードでもあったけ
懐かしい顔に見けて
ほんの数行ノスタルジーを
調子はどうですか
忙しくしていますか
無我夢中で探しまわってた
あの夢の具合はどんなだい
気分転換くらいのノリで
一緒に歌わないか
そして無我夢中で探しまわってた
あの夢の続きを語り合おうよ
明日は頑張ろうぜ
今はそこにある未来へ
駆け出して さぁ 行こう
This story is a work of fiction.
The people and groups are fictitious, but the themes relating to food and life are firmly based in reality. Visiting the places and facilities used as models can be dangerous and may result it contracting diseases from the animals. Please enjoy this story as a work of fiction.
Yay! New piglets!
わぁ　新しい豚だ
So cute!
カワイイ
ホント　このサイズから大きくならなきゃいいのにな
Yeah. It's too bad that they
have to grow bigger than this.
また数カ月後に肉になっちゃうのかぁ
They're all gonna become meat
in a few months again...
先生　２年になったら実績発表とかいうのがありますよね？
Sensei, we all have to submit a project
report in our second year, right?
ええ　専門的な研究班に分かれてのプロジェクト活動がありますよ
Yes, you'll split up into specialized
research groups and do a project.
私　ホエー豚の研究やりたいです
I'd like to research whey-fed pigs.
I learned in class that if you feed pigs whey,
which is a byproduct of making cheese,
授業でちょっと習ったんですけど
チーズを作るときに出るホエーを与えることで
肉がおいしくなるって
they produce better-tasting meat.
ええ
Yes.
生き物を食べる食べないで　私も色々考えたんですけど
I've thought a lot about whether
I should eat animals or not,
結局肉おいしいなってところから離れられなくて
but I can't deny the fact
that meat tastes good.
Still, it's an issue that I'll
have to keep thinking about
でも　この業界にいたらずっと考えなきゃいけない問題だと思うから
if I stay in this line
of business, so...
えっと…自分の好きな分野の隅っこに置けば
If I keep it in mind while
doing what I want to do...
うんと…チーズ作りながら家畜のことも常に意識しておきたいっていうか…
Like, I want to stay aware of livestock,
even while I make cheese.
あああ！　うまく説明できない！
Ugh, I just can't explain it very well!
いや　分かるよ
No, I get what you mean.
うん　うん
Yeah.
チーズ加工と食肉加工のタッグね
A cheese and meat processing
tag team, huh?
エゾノーブランド豚をつくり出してみては　どうかしら？
Why don't we create an
Ezonoo-branded pig?
イエス！
Yes!
Let's not name them this time.
今回は名前付けないでおこう
Yeah.
だよね　やっぱ名前付けたら感情移入しちゃうし
If you do, you'll just end up
caring too much about them.
いや　お前の名前はベーコンだ
No, your name is Bacon!
You're going to name them again?
また名前を付けるだと？
付けます！
I am!
You're going to make yourself
miserable all over again?
苦しい思いを繰り返すというのか
先生　前に言いましたよね
Sensei, you told us before
that we shouldn't get too
comfortable with what we have.
ここでいいと決め付けてそこに居座り続けるなよって
It'd be easier if I could just accept
生き物を食うってこんなもんだよねって
割り切って達観しちゃえば楽だけど
that this is how it has
to be if we eat animals,
but I just can't do it!
俺は…それはやっぱ嫌です
達観してそこに満足して居座るのは
You can't just accept and get
used to that fact,
once you see these guys...
こいつら見ちゃったらもうできません
この先悩んで悩んで悩みまくっても
But even if you continue to grapple
with this for a very long time,
you still may never arrive
at a satisfactory answer.
満足のいく答えは出ないかもしれんぞ
中学んときのノイローゼに比べたら
Compared to the nervous breakdown
I had in junior high,
悩みがいのある問題ですよ
this is an issue worth thinking about.
All right!
よし！　出荷まで付き合うぞ！　ベーコン
I'm gonna take care of you
until the end, Bacon!
懲りないやつだなぁ　お前
Man, you never learn.
You're hopeless, Hachiken-kun...
しょうがないなぁ　八軒君は
You're Pork Cutlet Bowl, Ham, Char Siu,
Pork Soup, Pork Cutlet, Ginger Pork.
カツ丼　ハム　チャーシュー
豚汁　とんかつ　しょうが焼き
全員に名前付ける気かよ
Now you're naming all of them?!
どＭだ
A serious masochist.
バカだ　お前頭いいけどバカだ
Idiot! You're smart, but an idiot!
何だよー
C'mon, guys!
あんたねぇ　私たちが豚肉食べられなくなったら
You'd better take responsibility
責任取りなさいよ！
if none of us can eat pork anymore!
そ～だ　そ～だ！
Yeah, she's right!
責任を取れ～！
Take responsibility!
You'd better!
責任取ってくれよ～！
そ～だ　そ～だ！
Yeah!
の…残りのベーコン　みんなに食わせてやるよ！
I... I'll let you guys have
the rest of the bacon!
Yay!
Pig Pen
To be continued!!